

#### **Email**

iloudaros@upnet.gr

#### **Phone Number**

+30 6940504030

#### Languages

Greek

English

#### **Skills**

#### **Software**

C, C++, Java, Swift, Python, MatLab, Javascript, HTML, CSS, PHP

#### Hardware

Verilog

#### **Foundation**

ML

#### **Experienced** with

Office Suite, iWork Suite, GSuite, Trello, Monday

Github, Xcode, Atom, VSCode

#### Sigasi Studio

Adobe Creative Cloud, Final Cut Pro, Motion, Compressor, Vectornator, Pixelmator Pro, Figma

#### Others

Classical Piano, Break Dance, Jazz, Cheers, Acro





Ioannis Loudaros



# Ioannis Loudaros | Ιωάννης Λουδάρος

A passionate student of Computer Engineering and Informatics. With extended experience in event management and preeminent academic presence. Having already carried out ambitious endeavours in the fields of Art, Volunteering and Engineering, he is no stranger to challenges. Used to responsibilities, as the PR Person of the IEEE Student Branch of Patras. He is ultimately armed with technical knowledge, as well as, the art of communication and cooperation.

### Featured in



# The Uni.Times: IEEE Student Branch - University of Patras with Ioannis Loudaros

A small interview about the IEEE SB of the University of Patras. I was the PR Person at the time.

### **Education**

University of Patras, Computer Engineering and Informatics Department Integrated Masters in Computer Engineering and Informatics, 5th year (final).

2nd High School of Ilion

Graduated with Commendation.

## Volunteering

#### **Acting Team**

2nd High School of Ilion Sept 2013 - May 2016 · 3 yrs

#### **Journalism Team**

2nd High School of Ilion Sept 2013 - May 2015 · 2 yrs

#### **Fundraising, Social, Design**

IEEE SB UPatras May 2019 - Dec 2019 · 8 mos

### Courses

#### **Arduino essentials**

Seminar at the Mediterranean College

#### **MATLAB Onramp**

Associated with University of Patras

## **Experience**

# Reception at "Wave Sports" in Thera

Wave Sports · Aug 2016

Reception and preparation of the customers for the maritime activities.

#### **Freelance Video Editor**

Ongoing

Examples such as: "Φροντιστήρια Πουκαμισάς" (Video for the opening of the company's new building) and Beauty Aifel (Instagram promotion Video).

#### Secretary / PR Supervisor

IEEE SB UPatras
Dec 2019 - Jun 2021 · 1 yr 7 mos

With a really active presence in the organisation and coordination of many scientific and social events like:
IEEE Day, IEEE Xtreme, Spooktacular Uparty, Google HashCode Hub etc.

#### Mentor

IEEE SB UPatras Jun 2021 - Present

#### **Insider (Tour Guide)**

Athens Insiders · Part-time Aug 2021 - Sep 2022

Designed and executed tours with special content.

#### **Model and Actor**

Attitude Models · Part-time Jan 2022 - Present

Did extra roles for films and ads for brands such as "What'sUp", "Payze", "Nescafe" etc.

## **Projects**

You can have access to selected projects listed here and more, by clicking the GitHub link on the previous page.

#### nomnomr.

Associated with University of Patras - Software Engineering

A tool for the nights when you wanna kill your friends. Group orders have never been easier and more fun.

#### CoVID69

Associated with University of Patras - Programming for the World Wide Web

A University Project on how to blow Covid-19 away. Community based infection reporting.

#### Order

Associated with University of Patras - Advanced Information Systems

Set of logistic tools that track objects of interest inside of a building using RFID technology, a mobile app, and QR Codes.

#### **Hot Sauce**

Associated with University of Patras - Principles of Programming Languages

A simple Lexical and Syntactical Analyser for a C-like language made with Flex and Bison.

#### **Paralllelli**

Associated with University of Patras - Parallel Computing

University Project on the subject of Parallel Computing. It explores parallelization techniques using OpenMP, MPI, or a combination of both.

#### **Tourism Analysis using the Eurostat Python package**

Associated with University of Patras -

Using data from Eurostat, we get to some conclusions related to tourism in Greece and Spain.

### **Publications**

#### <!- To Be Decided, something combining ML and Hardware Design -->

Associated with University of Patras - Diploma Thesis

This is my diploma thesis. I am in the process of deciding its specific application.

# **Art Projects**

#### Sound Art Seminar for Music Professors by Panagiotis Vasilellis

The goal of this seminar was to prove that students with no musical studies -but with aesthetics and passion- can create impressive audio experiences. I was the curator of the ambient sounds that tied the individual sounds of the students.

#### Video for March 25th

Creation of a video that contained historical and cultural information around the anniversary. It was projected at a relevant event.

#### "ΤΙΣΙΣ, ΜΙΑ ONTOTHTA ΤΗΣ ΘΑΛΑΣΣΑΣ" by Panagiotis Vasilellis

Performance based on sound art and narration. It was part of a sea themed Art Exhibition . It was presented in a gallery in Plaka, Athens. I was the narrator.

#### **Biographical Video for Kiki Dimoula**

Biographical video for the biggest greek poetess alive. It contained an exclusive recording of the poem "Dust" by Aristea Papalexandrou.